Guide to the Elias Bowen papers, 1820-1852.
Bowen, Elias papers, 1820-1852.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Elias Bowen papers, 1820-1852.
2111
Elias Bowen, 1791-1871.
50 items,
Correspondence.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Letters to Bowen during his pastorates at Utica, Ithaca, Cazenovia, Locke, and Moravia, New York, written by clergymen and others concerning revivals at Ithaca and elsewhere, work of the Cazenovia Seminary and Wesleyan University, and Methodism in Central New York.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Methodist preacher, trustee of Cazenovia Seminary.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Letters to Bowen during his pastorates at Utica, Ithaca, Cazenovia, Locke, and Moravia, New York, written by clergymen and others concerning revivals at Ithaca and elsewhere, work of the Cazenovia Seminary and Wesleyan University, and Methodism in Central New York.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Bowen, Elias, 1791-1871.; Cazenovia Seminary.; Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.)
Subjects:
Methodism.; Methodist Church--Clergy.; Revivals.
Places:
New York (State)--Religion.; Cazenovia (N.Y.); Ithaca (N.Y.); Locke (N.Y.); Moravia (N.Y.); Utica (N.Y.)
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Letters to Elias Bowen
  - Addressed to Utica, from Rev. Charles Giles in Baltimore, Md. [about a conference in Baltimore - mentions religious revival], May 17, 1820 (Box 1)
  - Addressed to Ithaca, from Rev. W. Case in York, U. Canada (p.m. Buffalo), Dec. 7, 1825 (Box 1)
  - Addressed to Sauquoit, from John Perkins in Ithaca (p.m. Clinton) [telling of the religious situation while he is away], Mar. 12, 1826 (Box 1)
  - Addressed to Sauquoit, from John Perkins in Ithaca (p.m. New Hartford) [about relgious fervor growing in Ithaca], Oct. 22, 1826 (Box 1)
  - Addressed to Sauquoit, from John Perkins in Ithaca (p.m. Utica) [mentions names of Ithacans who are converting], Dec. 7, 1826 (Box 1)
  - Addressed to Sauquoit, from John Perkins in Ithaca, Jan. 12, 1827 (Box 1)
  - Addressed to Sauquoit, from D. Ayers (p.m. Ithaca), Feb. 13, 1827 (Box 1)
  - Addressed to Sauquoit, from Rev. David A. Shepard in Ithaca, Aug. 3, 1835 (Box 1)
  - Addressed to Sauquoit, from Rev. Nelson Rounds in Cazenovia, Feb. 15, 1836 (Box 1)
  - Addressed to Sauquoit, from Dr. Samual Luckey in New York [regarding the printing of a sermon in the "Quarterly"], Oct. 4, 1837 (Box 1)
  - Addressed to Cazenovia, from D.A. Shpard in Norwich, Nov. 19, 1938 (Box 1)
  - Addressed to Cazenovia, from D.A. Shpard in Norwich, Feb. 19, 1939 (Box 1)
  - Addressed to Cazenovia, from Bishop Elijah Hedding in Lansingburgh, Oct. 30, 1840 (Box 1)
  - Addressed to Cazenovia, from D.A. Shepard in Ithaca, Feb. 17, 1841 (Box 1)
  - Addressed to Cazenovia, from Rev. V.M. Coryell in Cooperstown, Mar. 2, 1841 (Box 1)
  - Addressed to Cazenovia, from Nelson Rounds in Cooperstown (Hartwick), Mar. 29, 1841 (Box 1)
  - Addressed to Sauquoit, from James L. Alverson [secretary of Lyceum] in Cazenovia, Jan. 20, 1843 (Box 1)
  - Addressed to Sauquoit, from Augustus W. Smith [secretary of Wesleyan Univ.] in Middletown, Ct., July 4, 1844 (Box 1)
  - Addressed to Sauquoit, from Rev. Bostwick Hawley in Ithaca, Feb. 26, 1845 (Box 1)
  - Addressed to Sauquoit, from A.W. Smith at Wesleyan Univ. (p.m. Middletown, Ct.), Mar. 28, 1845 (Box 1)
  - Addressed to Sauquoit, from B. Hawley in Ithaca, Nov. 4, 1845 (Box 1)
  - Addressed to Sauquoit, from B. Hawley in Ithaca, Nov. 15, 1845 (Box 1)
  - Addressed to Sauquoit, from N. Rounds in Auburn, Mar. 3, 1846 (Box 1)
  - Addressed to Sauquoit, from N. Rounds in Auburn, Mar. 17, 1846 (Box 1)
  - Addressed to Ithaca, from B. Hawley in Wilkesbarre, Pa., Aug. 10, 1846 (Box 1)
  - Addressed to Ithaca, from Rev. A.J. Dana in Clinton, Nov. 6, 1846 (Box 1)
  - Addressed to Ithaca, from B. Hawley in Wilkesbarre, Pa., Nov. 7, 1846 (Box 1)
  - Addressed to Ithaca, from N. Rounds in Auburn, Nov. 30, 1846 (Box 1)
  - Addressed to Ithaca, from Rev. Charles B. Blakeslee in Fabius, Dec. 27, 1846 (Box 1)
  - Addressed to Ithaca, from T. Stocking in Norwich, June 21, 1847 (Box 1)
  - Addressed to Ithaca, from Rev. Lyman A. Eddy in Cazenovia [about funds for the seminary in Cazenovia], Mar. 29, 1847 (Box 1)
  - Addressed to Ithaca, from Rev. Daniel W. Bristol in Auburn, Aug. 10, 1847 (Box 1)
  - Addressed to Ithaca, from E. Hedding in Poughkeepsie, Oct. 6, 1847 (Box 1)
  - Addressed to Ithaca, from E. Hedding in Poughkeepsie, Nov. 9, 1847 (Box 1)
  - Addressed to Ithaca, from N. Rounds in Auburn, Dec. 13, 1847 (Box 1)
  - Addressed to Ithaca, from A.J. Dana in Binghamton, Feb. 23, 1848 (Box 1)
  - Addressed to Ithaca, from B. Hawley in Wilkesbarre, Pa., Feb. 28, 1848 (Box 1)
  - Addressed to Ithaca, from N. Rounds in Auburn, Apr. 12, 1848 (Box 1)
  - Addressed to Ithaca, from D.A. Shepard in Binghamton, June 21, 1848 (Box 1)
  - Addressed to Locke, from A.J. Dana in Owego, Feb. 24, 1849 (Box 1)
  - Addressed to Moravia, from Rev. Henry Bannister at O.C. Seminary (Cazenovia), June 12, 1849 (Box 1)
  - Addressed to Moravia, from B. Hawley in Oxford, Sept. 8, 1849 (Box 1)
  - Addressed to Moravia, from Prof. John Johnston at Wesleyan Univ. (Middletown, Ct.), Oct. 27, 1849 (Box 1)
  - Addressed to Moravia, from Bishop Leonidas Lent Hamline in Peoria, Illinois, Oct. 6, 1850 (Box 1)
  - Addressed to Moravia, from C. Blakeslee in Preble, Feb. 2, 1852 (Box 1)
  - From Dr. Filch in New York (707 Broadway), Mar. 10, 1852 (Box 1)
- Letters to Mrs. Abigail Bowen from Elias Bowen
  - Addressed to Sauquoit from Stockbridge (p.m. Vernon), Aug. 4, 1836 (Box 1)
  - Addressed to Sauquoit from Ithaca, Aug. 28, 1838 (Box 1)
  - Addressed to Cazenovia from Baltimore, Md., May 26, 1840 (Box 1)
  - Addressed to Moravia from Sherburne, July 21, 1849 (Box 1)